Michael Metry - Software Engineer

647-937-4240 | michaelmetry3@gmail.com | Markham, ON | Linkedin Profile

Objective

I have completed my final year of Software Engineering at Ontario Tech University. My goals are to receive valuable and long-life experiences working with a software-based company. This would allow me to apply what I was taught in university and incorporate it into building and developing software products. Lastly, I am very confident in learning new concepts quickly and applying them to individually or group-based projects.

Experience

Camp GA | Counselor

June 2022 - August 2022

- Engaged with children between 7-8 years of age with a variety of activities provided.
- Supervised children and provided a safe and friendly space.
- Demonstrated leadership, communication, and teamwork skills with co-workers.

SMSJB Coptic Orthodox Church | Volleyball Coach

November 2018 - June 2019

- In charge of providing lessons to children during weekends such as serving, spiking, etc.
- Explained the rules and setup of a regular volleyball match.
- Incorporated leadership, communication, and teamwork to children by providing tips of the sport.

ASP Computers | Entry Volunteer

June 2016 - June 2018

- Experienced working with hardware and software in building and configuring PCs.
- Handling customer service with the use of TeamViewer Application to resolve technical problems.
- Developed an understanding of network configuration by incorporating with electronic devices.

Education

Ontario Tech University | Oshawa, ON | Software Engineering September 2019 – April 2023

Skills

Python, MySQL, HTML & CSS, Microsoft SQL, C/C++, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Java, VS Code, Visual Studio IDE, Firebase Database, Git/GitHub, Google Cloud Platform, Google Kubernetes, Codeblocks IDE, PHP, Flutter & Dart, Linux OS, Atom IDE, PyCharm IDE, IntelliJ IDEA, Confluent Kafka, Apache Spark, React, Tailwind CSS

Projects

Capstone Smart Blinds System (Python, Android Studio, Java, C/C++, JSON, Firebase Database)

- Designed using a mobile app to control lighting and temperature of a home.
- Arduino sensors were used to detect the level of light, temperature, and time values in a home.
- Incorporated Machine Learning libraries to let the blinds recognize the patterns in a daily routine and the blinds will automatically adjust, making your life effortless through user preferences.

Video Game Website (HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, WAMPSERVER)

- Incorporated the use of HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, and WAMPSERVER to design a web application game which
 involved avoiding obstacles falling from the sky and getting your character to the highest level possible
- The WAMPSERVER was used to record responses when users signs up on the website and leaving comments at the end of the game for possible improvements.